Suraj Hande

Senior Software Engineer

surajhande@hotmail.com

+91 - 9700017285

surajhande_1

Summary

A Software Engineer with 4+ years of professional experience developing customer-facing software. Ability to contribute at all levels of the software development life cycle.

Skills & Competencies

Android SDK: 4+ years of experience with applications published in Google Play Store.

Oracle Certified Java Programmer (OCJP).

Experience programming with Kotlin and Kotlin Coroutines.

3+ years of programming in C++.

Strong with general data structures and algorithms.

Knowledge of architectural patterns like MVP and MVVM.

Knowledge of Material Design guidelines.

Hands-on with Android Jetpack components and libraries like Retrofit, Dagger 2, Glide etc.

Experience working with REST and JSON.

Unit testing with JUnit, Espresso etc.

Hands-on with version control systems like Git and SVN.

Work Experience

Polycom (NYSE: PLT)

Hyderabad

Senior Software Engineer

September 2016 - Ongoing

Software Developer at Polycom voice endpoints team, responsible for designing, developing and integrating UC system software features for new and existing products.

I work in an agile environment developing software features in scrum sprints.

Responsibilities:

Developing software for VoIP phones ensuring fast and reliable performance.

Actively participate in the product development phase.

Take ownership of modules and provide ways to improve customer experience.

Interact with partners and stakeholders ensuring product compliance and integrity.

Tools & Frameworks used:

Java 8, Android SDK, C++ 11, Qt, Git, SVN

Intern

December 2015 - August 2016

Software Intern for the Polycom voice product team. I was responsible for developing tools and plugins to help with monitoring and debugging network issues for their upcoming VoIP devices.

Tools & Frameworks used:

C, C++, TCP/UDP, Wireshark

Education

Computer Science and Engineering

Bachelor of Technology from August 2012 to June 2016

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University.

LInks

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/surajhander/

GitHub: https://github.com/srjhnd
Portfolio: https://srjhnd.github.io/
PlayStore: http://tiny.cc/tkwviz